[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
uh
knowledge is power
[Music]
sober october in review welcome my
friends to the junkyard love podcast it
is i
your host your creator of the john care
love podcast
jay grunt so today i wanted to make this
episode
to go over kind of my experience with
sober october um not that it makes me
super special just by doing it just by
completing it
um but i feel like it's actually a lot
farther out of reach for a lot of us
than we realize
we're so uh caught up in our habits
you know me myself of course uh
just we're caught in the same loops and
we don't seem to see the benefits of
taking a break from our vices or taking
a break from our urges or
really looking at why we should question
our habits our habitual
default mode network moves that make our
identity right
so what i did for sober october 2020
was i gave up i did no social media of
any sort i didn't know
alcohol i didn't know weed i didn't know
masturbation and i did no
coffee no caffeine those are all things
that
that um are are not
necessarily difficult for me to give up
um but parts of
of who i am and parts of my habitual
life
um things that i enjoy and then things
that i just do
just out of habit um i think a lot of
you can relate with waking up and
you kind of just you just feel a little
uh until you get your cup of coffee
right there's
it's part of our part of our character
is
being coffee consumers not everybody
drinks coffee but in our culture
nowadays this is a
it's a an addictive wonderful drug that
we all
that we all uh partake in is coffee
uh caffeine i used to i've had issues
with coffee before
or caffeine before rather i used to
drink a ton of energy drinks
um and then my sleep schedule was all
super crazy um i
worked night shift for five years and so
my nocturnal just sleepy
weirdness was in full effect
so i would consume pre-workout which has
a ton of caffeine
um i would consume one to two energy
drinks a day or a night
and that was just what i did i just i
pretty much
just went to the store without thinking
about you just go to the gas station and
you just get your energy drinks because
you know that if you don't have them
you're gonna hit a wall and you're gonna
feel just super sleepy and sad at work
and you don't want that
so um i hadn't ever
quit caffeine i had lowered my caffeine
intakes
severely which helps greatly with
anxiety that's something that a lot of
us overlook i think when it comes to
anxiety
and lack of sleep and sleeping
thoroughly throughout the night
uh there's it seems so obvious and on
the surface right like we know that
caffeine makes us feel amped but
we somehow you know disconnect it from
my god i
slept so shitty last night well if you
had a cup of coffee or you had a monster
at 4 pm whatever it is stuff lasts in
your system for a while i think it still
has like pretty big effects 6 hours
later is what it is
but regardless so i wanted to give up
caffeine
for 30 days i did that successfully i
did not
go back and i did have
i think a total of four instances where
i technically drank coffee but it was
decaf
two of the times it was actually just a
black cup of coffee we got some decaf
downstairs and i just did it just so i
can like sit down and get some work done
to try to trick my mind into that
habitual because i
i write and i work well like having my
morning cup of coffee i'm extra creative
in the morning and such
so i wanted to trick my mind into having
that cup of joe
um it was weird like i knew that it
wasn't caffeine though so it was just
mildly unsatisfying it was i don't know
it
didn't hit the spot honestly having the
decaf cup i think i might have even been
better just
saying completely no like no if it has
any sort of caffeine let's just
not do it 30 days 31 days whatever it
was um
and then i had two other times where i
went to a place in town to get a protein
shake
and i had them add part of the
ingredients is coffee but i just had
them do decaf coffee so i got two
protein shakes that
had decaf in them um when i came back
onto the scene november 1st i woke up
and it was a sunday and i was like
oh man i can have a cup of coffee i was
so hyped
i drove to red leaf i got a cup of
coffee i saw a friend who haven't seen
for a while so that was nice seeing her
through the drive-through
and i came back and i i was drinking it
and i was working on some stuff some
audio work
um and i was amped i was jittery i was
like i loved it but
after a couple hours actually i noticed
i was i was literally biting down on my
jaw
a little bit like my i was tensed up in
my
in my jaw area my face area and my leg
was twitching
um it's interesting because it's this
enjoyable high
right you know we love that when you're
just kind of carefree and you have
it's it's energy and there's almost
motivation in that energy
we're all used to that coffee high but i
think
i'm someone who's very aware of how i
feel at all times
and so i really like i really enjoyed
studying myself when it comes to this
like okay i have this first cup of
coffee
and i like it but i'm pretty aimed right
now like am i
you know is this a better feeling than
equanimity
is this a better feeling than the
homeostasis that i had
or seemingly had for the the last 31
days
so it was interesting and then it's been
a couple days since that day i've had a
cup of coffee every day in the morning i
really enjoy my my morning cup of coffee
my brain works the best my brain seems
to be most days the clearest
upon rising and so i like to um and i
i also got my awesome roommates got me a
yeti coffee cup
so i can go outside and do my
meditations and yoga out in the cold and
still
not have a cold cup of coffee by the end
of it so that's wonderful
um but i did notice last night i
actually
i had my cup of coffee in the morning
and then i kind of hit a brick wall
at work last night at like 5 p.m
and i had a cup of coffee and it was
interesting
because i was i enjoyed the cup of
coffee
but i was very aware as i was drinking
it like this probably isn't the best
idea
it's probably better for me to power
through this tired feeling that i'm
having
go walk around at work or go kind of
just take a break from the computer
screen that's making me tired
um but i but what was easy was that
that instant fix right like you can go
pour a cup of coffee you get the smell
you get the whole thing
and within 20 minutes when you're able
to drink it when it's not too dang hot
you feel fine you feel alert you feel
awake you have energy pep in your step
but it has adverse effects because at
night like i had trouble falling asleep
last night i drank that cup of coffee
way too late i had two cups of coffee
when
i'm not really used to that much
caffeine right now so it got me pretty
amped up
so there's there's something to be said
for that i think to round out the coffee
caffeine thing
i think that we could look at a lot of
these um
especially energy energy drinks man i
used to be obsessed with their drinks i
think they're delicious
um i was never really a soda guy but but
energy drinks
uh just all of them i love to try all
the new flavors
um but you know we got to just keep an
eye on ourselves we got to keep an eye
on
um just being able to be okay without it
i think um not having you know not only
the caffeine headaches that you get when
you don't have one like
we also notice it's almost like that the
word hangry we hear that a lot
um we get almost a kind of a slight
headache
you know the caffeine withdrawal
headache and it makes us almost grumpy
and just like with hangry it's kind of
this thing where we're okay
with being kind of a turd or kind of
being a jerk or kind of
being a brat whatever it is like we're
grown adults
but we're not able to really connect the
fact that we're hungry or we need
caffeine or we make it okay to be
snappy or like not our best versions of
ourselves because we have this craving
that we really want like well
i'll be happy don't talk to me before
before my first cup of coffee
i don't know i it's it's something
interesting i know a lot of people are
in that bubble
um i've certainly been a caffeine
consumer i mean
i started working i was 15 and i just
started hitting the edge drinks pretty
hard back then
so taking the 30-day break the 31-day
break was
i'm glad i'm glad i did it um i'm going
to be a lot more
aware of my my caffeine intake i've kind
of just like let it rip the last couple
days just see like what do i really feel
like doing
but like i said last night i had i had
the instance where where i
said shouldn't have drank that i should
have just powered through the little
sleepiness that i felt or
maybe the food that i ate earlier was
making me sleepy so i can make better
food choices so i don't have to rely on
coffee
later you know your food is your energy
source as well your um
your water intake too so when it comes
to water intake
water intake is super important i mean
everybody always says that but it's this
thing you know if you listen to this
podcast i'm always chiming in about i'm
always going on about it
i have my friend devin sins sims on here
talking about kangen water
which i will totally butcher it and i'll
sound like a total dork trying to
explain it but
the the water is like more oxidized it's
more filtered
it's more electrically charged it helps
it's broken down better
so it uh penetrates our cells a little
bit better
um and i i think you know we all know
plenty of people
you know if if if you're saying
millennial age or younger listening to
this podcast
i have a feeling you know your parents
or your grandparents
or even your older co-workers it might
be very normal for them to
never ever drink any water i mean i i
know
i feel like i know hundreds of people
who it's part of their personality it's
like a joke to not drink water
and those same people have like back
pain and they have issues with colon
and in digestive issues
and uh you know their knees are and
their ankles hurt and their hips hurt
and they have
you know again bad back i'm not saying
that that water is the cure to all these
things but you really need to think
about what we are you know we're
very liquidy beings we're made of
tons of water and i'm telling you uh
slight headaches don't just jump to
ibuprofen like how much water have you
drank
you'll notice a lot of times when
someone tells you to drink water or
you're drinking extra water
you you you end up feeling a lot better
but it just kind of breezes over like
you just
you're just noticing that you don't feel
the pain or discomfort anymore the
headache anymore
and so you just kind of go about your
day but when bad things happen or
illnesses feel feel like they're they're
setting in or
we feel we just feel kind of crappy we
we really put a note in that we're
always like oh get that away i don't
want to feel bad i just want to feel
comfort
comfort comfort comfort and being aware
of that i think is important and i think
water helps a lot with that because
when you're not drinking enough water
you have all these little things that
happen to your body throughout the day
and happen to your to your brain and
happen
um you know inflammation is a huge thing
that i think water helps reduce
um and we just get we just get used to
reaching for the instant fix the
ibuprofen you know i've been there i've
totally used to just take so much
freaking ibuprofen
i would actually have um you know
everybody knows that drinking dehydrates
you
and i would i would drink you know even
if i had just two ipas
um i would go to bed i would put four
ibuprofen on my bedside table
so in the middle of night or in the
morning i wake up and as soon as i
started to feel like maybe the slightest
headache i would just be like oh i
broken
pop those drink some water go back to
sleep and you wake up and you feel fine
but i think we we should
really be saving those those you know
ibuprofen's great these inflammatory
things like
it's all aspirin it's all it's all great
stuff that we have but
we don't need to just be running to it
every single time
um i think that you know for me
personally i think that a lot of doing
that like tore up my gut lining
i think that um the effects that it had
the negative effects though very hard to
to pinpoint exactly
what they were i think that the negative
effects
just weren't really weighing out me
being able to just deal with like
hey i have a slight headache and once i
get moving once i drink some water
if i do 15 minutes of stretching and i
go outside and i get some fresh air take
maybe take my shoes off and get my feet
on the ground bare feet
do some breath work and stretching and
moving around like the slight hangover
the slight headache that i have or the
achiness or whatever it is
will likely go away um and i urge you
guys to try that too
so if you're someone who just habitually
pops ibuprofen and you don't drink water
you know do your thing but just you know
be aware of it
be aware is this the best thing to help
me long term we're always looking to
put a peg and how do i feel the best
right this second
how do i feel good now and that's not
always the best answer for
our body on a spectrum you know our our
life
on a holistic long-term
timeline you know and so
water was great i really enjoyed the
kangen water i had a couple
a couple different things it was nice to
just go over to my friend's house
and uh converse with him for a little
bit as i would fill up the water jugs
and he'd run me through the whole thing
um i'm very picky about water so i i
noticed the taste i feel like
a lot so the kangen water i don't know i
won't talk too much about it because i
really don't know a ton about it but
that's what i drank during the month
of october and it was great and i
enjoyed it and i hit my gallon a day
and
i think that everybody should try to
shoot for that i think every single time
you
when you take a drink of water don't
make it just
oh i'm going to wait time thirsty to
take a drink of water or i'm going to
force myself to drink water it's like
when you do take take water try to add
in
try to count certain gulps try to say
i'm going to try to drink for
five seconds straight or i'm going to
take
a lot one more gulp than i normally
would just because you know you're
trying to increase your intake
and then after a while you know after a
couple weeks when you're kind of forcing
yourself to get into that new habit of
drinking water
always having a water bottle with you
always have water bottles in your car
whatever it is um just always having
access to these things and not going for
the soda not going for the energy drinks
not going for another cup of coffee
just quenching your thirst with water at
all times
um it it starts to make it
you you become more thirsty more often
but it's a good thing
you enjoy drinking water like you want
to get more water
in your body definitely thanks you for
it and i will say
i think there's something about waking
up hydrated
our body goes through a ton when we're
sleeping i think our body
cycles through just a ton of our
hydration
and i know me like if i would rather
wake up in the middle of night to have
to go take a leak
than wake up just completely dried out
and feeling all crusty and dusty and
rusty you know
so drink a ton of water um
it's good for you have water right next
to your bed every single night
and maybe try to make a habit to in the
mornings just wake up and drink water it
gets your digestive system going even
before you have a cup of coffee
just try to chug half a glass of water
good to go and then
stretch it out get it rolling um so
that's water
water went well um
i did let's see no no drinking
um that was that was a pretty easy one
for me i um
you know situationally in my life right
now i'm going through a lot of
um you know going going through going
through a breakup
it's like i really i don't want to drown
my sorrows you know i'm kind of
aged out of that sort of feeling i don't
want to just go get
blacked out drunk or anything but i did
notice like just the
the inevitable loneliness that i felt i
just and
i didn't have social media either so i
felt very disconnected
um i would kind of just like i'd walk in
and basically see just like my
my roommate and he's working he's got
headphones in and like we wouldn't
really interact
like there'd be multiple days where i
just wouldn't really see anybody
and i felt very lonely i felt very like
i you know i wanted to like
text other people just to like i guess
talk about myself or
see what they're up to or um i wanted to
the urge to drink came with i wanted to
hit up my friends
and just say like hey you want to go
grab an ipa do you want to go grab a
beer do you want to go meet at this
place
and it's it's interesting because
there was a lot of me that was feeling
guilty about that like oh man i thought
i kicked this like
this urge to drink you know because i um
i've never been like a
a big alcoholic i've never been a a huge
heavy heavy drinker i don't really like
to get like
blacked out all the time certainly have
but um
i mean my preference is just have a
couple beers and you know
a [\h__\h] session um it kind of like
helps me shut down
my overly neurotic overly um
you know aware conscientions um
uh yeah just just overly
neurotic thoughts and helps me that
social lubricant right i'm sure we all
know
how it is where you just kind of feel
awkward almost or you feel
self-conscious even or
whatever it is that alcohol helps us all
with in social settings i totally get
that i'm totally with you on that
um but really really just going through
this this sad time i really just noticed
my
my urge to not just get close to my
friends but i wanted i really wanted to
just go
have a couple beers you know like uh it
would it'd feel better if i just had a
couple beers but i also am someone who
i deal with i have major depression
depressive disorder
and when i get carried away like say i
have
you know i have beers three times a week
like or whatever it is or i go to
too overboard or my diet's super crappy
and then i have a couple beers
sometimes it's all fun and games it's
all great i'm having a great time and
then i go home
i'm at home and my depression just
starts really kicking my ass i just
can't really
grab hold of it because you know the
couple drinks is enough to kind of
it uh you know alcohol is a depressant
so it gets harder to grab control of the
depression symptoms and
i'm sure anybody with anxiety alcohol
may
may affect you in the same way so
um alcohol
i'm glad that i did the break um me
personally
when it comes to my journey for drinking
i started drinking i think i was
14. um i just you know i grew up as
a skateboarder with no
structure like we were just kind of you
know
i guess kind of like the rebellious type
like you know we weren't the first
people to drink at our high school or
our middle school or whatever it was
but we were definitely like the
the amount of people that got drunk with
my group of friends for their first time
was fairly high
there's this weird dichotomy and i'm not
saying i'm like proud of this or this is
something that i
i aspire to to put put on my chest
but alcohol has just been immensely
normal in my life when i was way younger
my parents would have like multiple
parties my parents would go out
pretty much every weekend um they had
like a favorite bar in town that
they would always go to we'd always had
a ton of bikers who were always they
were always drinking
um when i was a young kid and so alcohol
has just been incredibly
normalized to me and i think that a lot
of people especially in small towns like
our town
it's it's all it's just incredibly
normal it's just what you do
um you know what it doesn't have to be
binge drinking it could just be kind of
like it's just a little stress reliever
like you have a glass of wine or
i do this blah blah it's
it's something that can certainly grab
hold of us though if if we're not
careful
just noticing my like my urges when i
quit
this 30 days i've i've quit in the last
two years
i i took a break um started 30 days and
then i went to 45 and then it was just
just a few months just because i was so
um it was kind of when i when i first
had my you know spiritual awakening
kind of rebirth ego death i started
learning all this philosophy i started
learning all this self-help started
obsessively listening to guys like tony
robbins all these things i basically
like
was inserting meaning into my life i
just didn't think about the booze
i i was just so obsessed with what i was
doing here
um like like my work and my future work
and just learning about these things
they were just so enthralling to me that
i didn't really think about booze i
wasn't really hanging out with anybody
um but
but you know inevitably your life you
can't just like stay locked in your
basement your whole life you know like
it gets to the point where
um you almost when you like don't hang
out with anybody don't talk to
anybody there's almost like a slight
agoraphobia that we step into
that is just this craving for social
interaction
but you feel almost crippled by it and
so when you're when you're overly
neurotic and overly analytical about
your thoughts and what you're saying
in the room and everything that's
happening in the room um
and and you have maybe you you
you relate to someone as someone who has
adhd where your attention span it's very
difficult to keep your attention span
alcohol helps those things in social
situations especially like being at a
bar being at a concert where it's loud
there's a lot going on there's lights
there's people walking over here there's
people walking over there
there's people walking in the door maybe
there's people looking at me maybe
there's not
did i say that thing wrong did i say
that thing right am i explaining this
correctly what does this person think
about me there's all these overly
just ridiculous things that in social
settings especially nowadays
many of us go through and um
i i don't think that i'm alone when i
say
having a drink or two drinks or a shot
or whatever it is
it's it's a very personal
internal thing um we you know we of
course enjoy it like it's like i like to
have a couple drinks
um i i i can let go i don't really care
what i'm doing maybe i'm more apt to
kind of sing along to the song that's
playing
maybe that's what i need to get some
karaoke in me and in the end you know i
danced around i sang around with my
friends
that's worthy like it pulled me out of
my shell a little bit and out of my
out of my head right um
it's it's it's interesting
um just because it's so
normal there there are a lot of effects
of alcohol
that i think a lot of us have a lot of
negative effects or a lot of um
addictions towards alcohol that we
aren't really able to admit to ourselves
or able to
look ours look ourselves in the eye when
it comes to right
um when we think of addicts where we
think of an alcoholic
you know we're always like anybody who
drinks
the first we're like oh i'm not that i'm
so far from that we have this image in
our head
of what an alcoholic is or what someone
who drinks too much
is we might even have um if you're
listener if you're a drinker
or even casually just once in a while
you might have kind of an image or a
friend someone you know you're like oh
they
they put they drink too much or they
whatever blah blah well
you know they probably have the same
thing in their eyes like they probably
aren't gonna say oh i'm an alcoholic or
oh i'm
whatever this is it's these labels stop
us from
really analyzing and taking um taking
ownership of
what we're dealing with because like who
[\h__\h] cares if if someone else thinks
you're an alcoholic you're the one who's
dealing with it
like if you're um you know like
obviously you don't want to be
destructive and just being ruining your
life and hurting people around you
driving drunk these sorts of things but
there's there's this internal
uh avoidance of admittance of our own
kind of like
habits that don't make us feel good you
know what the ego does is we take credit
for all the things that are good
but we reject all the things that are
bad like we push those away and we don't
want to see those because
we're protecting ourselves from that
pain in a sense so
um i i suppose
i suppose the no drinking thing is
i i it's it's helpful um
i i think it's still a slow a slow
journey for me um
i i i'm very much looking forward to i
had
um my my boss at work who's an old
friend
he took me out the night before my
birthday like we got off work
at like 9 9 30 something like that and
we went to one of my favorable bars
and just him and i sat there and shot
the [\h__\h] we had
one shot each and a beer
and it was nice you know just just to bs
and just listen to the touch tunes
i grew up in those environments um
i think a lot of people in small towns
grew up in you know
bar or like sports bar or restaurant
with
drinks environments and there's there's
a comfort to that
so i think going forward i think i'll
just be more ultra aware of my drinking
um more i'm gonna put put my foot down
with myself i think
as far as you know you get that you get
like one beer down
and or even two beers down and you're
feeling great and then you have this
like
yeah we'll do one more i will do one
more whatever it is a lot of us have our
own versions of that
but i think that maybe i'll just be more
sturdy and be like you know i feel
pretty good right now
and i don't have to keep this feeling
going
i don't have to it's okay if this
feeling only lasts for 15 more minutes
and then i'm kind of like a little tired
or i don't have to be desperately trying
to hold on to this
this light wonderful i'm drunk i'm not
thinking about
whatever my [\h__\h] or whatever my bad
day was
you know we're always trying to to
snapshot
oh i feel good right now i want to
maintain feeling good or i want to feel
even better
i think just kind of setting those
limits for ourselves
um it's important i you know i
i think also peer pressure is something
that that's worth addressing
um when it comes to drinking we
you know nobody likes drinking alone you
know it's something i notice when i
watch tv shows
people like drinking alone on tv shows
there's always like the person who's
just always
slamming a drink or there's there's
someone who's always they're able to
like
manage their stress very quickly with a
drink
which is probably some brainwashing
technique that we fall for
but um in in real life
when a lot of times when we order a
drink or order another beer or we want
to do a shot or whatever
then when the person that's with us
doesn't want to do one suddenly we don't
want to do one
right there's this strange
barrier where we don't want to drink
alone because then we feel shame for it
but i think that if we can kind of take
a look and stop and really assess
the awareness of how do i feel right now
like do
do i want another drink cool that's fine
yeah i do
okay and then if someone else doesn't
want to drink with you
if they don't want to take another shot
with you that's completely their choice
you know i think we have
a fun you know peer pressure
is is a funny thing because when it's
your friends we'll peer pressure each
other
and it all seems really fun in games but
you know i've i've observed quite a few
people who really didn't want another
shot
that didn't want another drink and the
group you know me included i've been a
part of this on the other side like come
on let's take another one blah blah
where we kind of just give in to that
and i think we can all kind of have
these
we can insert these boundaries where we
don't let anybody persuade us
where it's like i hit my drink limit and
this is the last that i'm drinking
tonight or this
is like okay yeah i'll have another beer
with you
but i'm gonna have a cup of water in
between or yeah i'll have another beer
with you but i'm gonna set an alarm on
my phone to where i'm not driving for
another hour or whatever it is
i i think finding something that's just
specific to you
in your life and how you grew up grew up
drinking
what you drink where you drink who you
drink with
you know there's not all this perfectly
directly right
um you know like completely wrong
completely right completely good
completely bad
we all have our own relationships with
alcohol
and our addictions and our pulls towards
our habits and
the things that we've been doing for a
long time that we don't really question
why we do them or what we get out of
them or what we want to get out of them
so setting up rules for yourself
there's real power in that you know
really sticking to your guns
and if you have trouble with that if you
have trouble saying
no if you have trouble like i'm not
going to drink and then you get to the
party and someone hands you a jello shot
and you're like
fine okay one jello shot and then all of
a sudden you're you know you're buying
an 8 ball and you got a trip to vegas
you know it happens
so just kidding um i i think that
taking like a 30 day lent or taking um
some sort of even two weeks just
something with
intentionality right something that says
i
am choosing to do these things no matter
what
and stick to that [\h__\h] man we're so
caught up our attention spans are so
quick our attention spans are so
this thing and this thing that we end up
just kind of giving into all of our
urges
at all times we're always just if
something comes up we're just like cool
i'm going to do that because it's going
to feel good right now
but feeling good right now doesn't
always equate to your best self it
doesn't always equate to
you know in the end being the person you
want to be you know sometimes you'll let
yourself
down when you just listen to those urges
you've got to listen to your kind of
higher consciousness
versions of yourself not just your lower
like let's just get pleasure
you know those sort of things so
speaking of pleasure i did
no masturbation for 30 31 days
it was certainly a lot longer than that
i think it might have been more like two
months
i've excuse me
i've done i've done no fap as it's
called
there's a lot of research on it honestly
there's a
you can go into a whole youtube rabbit
hole
of the different effects of it like a
lot of different
different traditions and religions kind
of have their say on these sorts of
things
i'm not sure which of them i believe i'm
not sure which of them
feels right i'm not sure which of them
resonates resonates with me
but i know that for me personally
controlling those sexual urges or
controlling those urges to
to masturbate or think about people in
that way
is incredibly helpful and it actually
helped me like really tame
tame the beast in me and i know it's so
weird to talk about right and there's
not really an area or
a world or a comfortable place to listen
to anything about
masturbation but it's it's a real thing
like i'm
i masturbate you probably masturbate and
it's something not something that we
were ever taught you know it's something
that's
an easy low-hanging urge
for us to all fall into um or i i've
talked here
about my my opinions on porn
um i i used to watch porn you know
like a lot of us watch porn but i just
don't really
i don't know it's it's uh i think that
it changes our minds in in intricate
ways i think that it's something that's
so
new i heard this thing once that was um
nobody nobody you know as far as on the
human timeline like how long we've been
alive
up until the internet came around or
maybe just before the internet when we
had like porno mags or whatever
the only types of types of people who
would have access to like this many like
you know quote unquote perfect physique
women doing whatever we want in the
craziest ways as many as you want to see
like you're tricking your brain when
you're watching these things like your
brain doesn't know the differences if
you're actually doing it or not
like is the only person who had access
to those things
before is people like genghis khan like
these these terrible leaders who would
just
you know take whatever they want like
without consent
i'm sure there was like an orgy asking
culture that that raised pretty supreme
for a long time but i don't know man i i
just think that
when you become really aware of your
thoughts we become really aware of your
urges when you become really aware of
what you're feeling and what your body's
telling you and what your mind reacts to
and how your mind convinces you of
certain things so you can get certain
things
you really start to notice how often
you're thinking
kind of head in the gutter right like
you're you're treating human beings
as kind of just like
how you can feel a sexual urge and it's
it's really interesting
sitting with that it's really um
you know it almost feels it almost feels
nasty of you it almost feels
it just starts to feel a little wrong
after a while
um just giving in to every single urge
that you have um
i think that but but once you can kind
of gain control once you can kind of
tap into it and tame that that beast
within you
you you kind of grow up and grow up out
of it and
you know it's dude listen there's
there's nothing wrong with masturbating
like the
your human body you're given the human
body you should explore the crap out of
the thing you should you should be just
like how you know you should be
exploring your consciousness
you should be exploring your body what
feels good what doesn't feel good
explore it in whatever way you want
but this world of uh
you know pornography and instagram
having just like
you know the hashtag will be hashtag
pacific northwest and it'll just be like
some girl's booty and a thong and
it's great right like it's it's badass
to see that
and it's really cool and like that's
we've
quickly transformed our culture into
just like this body positivity in a form
of like you can't shame me i'm gonna
sell myself in whatever way
like but i think that when we're
constantly
seeing on our phones we're scrolling and
we're seeing
uh you know like like half naked women
or we're seeing all of our friends in
their like
most uh vulnerable spots and we're like
in in the lone spot so it makes you
think
differently about these things i i don't
know how that
how that fares for us in the long run as
as humanity
you know um i follow the on on reddit
while i used to i followed the subreddit
that was porn free
and oh man if you want to see an
interesting side of the world you may
not know that exists there's like
so there's thousands and thousands of
people
primarily young men i think who are in
this porn free subreddit
who you know they'll they'll post like
hey i've been
uh i've done nofap now for seven months
and i feel better than i ever have in my
life and i've got control of my life and
all these things and i don't masturbate
to porn anymore and i don't watch porn
anymore blah blah i started when i was
11 or i started when i was
eight or uh i've been masturbating to
porn since
uh for the last 15 years blah blah these
people who have like all these erectile
dysfunctions they have
problems with their relationships they
have uh
just like very false ideas about
how how sex actually goes um
i think that a lot of our a lot of our
urges being like
really handed right to us on a platter
and really just put in our faces
and us never stopping to take control of
them especially as men
i don't know it changes us around
and i think that
just kind of coming to terms with
controlling those urges
and putting some structure around things
like masturbation
it's helpful and i i invite anybody i
know it sounds crazy and i know it's a
weird thing to talk about
and i'm not even sure if i'm talking
about it properly if there's such a
thing as talking about masturbation
properly but
i just want to i guess go over it you
know and say that he out exists and my
experience with it um
no no masturbation for the month of
october for sober october
um it went well i technically actually
two days before on the 29th
i technically failed uh i woke up to
uh um this is rather embarrassing but
but i woke up to some wet drawers i had
a wet dream situation
and it was interesting because i don't
even remember some sort of fantasy i
don't remember
any sort of like wonderful like
goddess chick just coming into my dream
world
and blowing my mind you know like it was
i actually woke up from a freaking night
terror
um which i i suffer with quite a bit uh
and i i woke up just covered in sweat
not feeling good
and and i was just kind of panicked and
my heart was heart rate was going really
fast and i had
kind of swung swung out of bed like woke
up really quickly
and i got up was going out of the
bathroom was like what the hell and you
know look down and
lo and behold you know something had
happened so
it's interesting what our bodies and
what our minds and what our psyche is
always trying to get us to do
but um uh i will note on that
the the shame that i felt um i was
pissed i was i was mad i was upset i was
discouraged i was like great i just
failed my sober october two days before
and i failed it
which is an interesting thing because it
took me
i went back to sleep um changed my
clothes whatnot
cleaned up went back to sleep and
i woke up and realized like that i had
been so mad
and i texted a friend and had told him
and i was like ashamed of myself i was
like so mad that i'd failed my sober
october but it was like my
unconscious reality that did this it was
me in the dream world
not even choosing to think these things
of course
so it was an interesting aspect noting
that
i i made myself feel guilt and shame for
something that really was not in my
control there so
that's another thing that i that i
noticed you know and that's something
that if you do any sort of 30 day
lengths if you do any sort of
um specific guidelines i will or i will
not do these things for this set amount
of time or this is
a value of mine that i no longer part
partake in in the same way that i do i
don't i don't bend on these things
here's my moral structure here is my
ethics
all these sort of things that we can
install within ourself with knowledge
it allows you to kind of observe what
your mind does when you
falter or what your mind does when you
have
the urges or like how you try to
convince yourself that it's okay and
then you feel bad about the next day or
how you try to justify
justifies a great word you know like
make our excuses for ourselves
um but so so me
to put a pit in that i guess for me
it was just very very nice to notice
that i made myself
feel so ashamed of that you know and
then once i woke up in the morning i
could i could say
oh that's okay man like what you want
what you're wanting to do here is make
yourself feel
shame but when i really analyze the
situation like you didn't do anything
wrong here
and shame is a helpful tool you know
guilt is a helpful tool because it tells
you like i don't want to be doing that
thing again
but in this situation i could i could
you know kind of insert
new thoughts into this thought process
of like making myself feel bad for
what happened when i was in a dream that
wasn't even a good dream it was a
terrifying dream i don't even remember
what it was i just know that i woke up
feeling terrible
and uh night terrors are kind of a
normal thing for me so
watching that guilt and that shame or
watching um you know
maybe you're an overeater maybe you're a
binge eater which is something that i
deal with sometimes as well
um like you'll eat just to feel better
just to feel that burst and it feels
good and then
five minutes later you're like you're
almost you're almost
out loud telling yourself how much you
hate yourself it just gets mean
quick sometimes so just observe when you
do that
is this helpful how can i listen to this
how can i rephrase these words
to myself how can i not only avoid
feeling this
shame this guilt this whatever my my
mind is trying to tell me that i should
or shouldn't do
how can i how can i work with this right
so really listening to those
things bringing awareness to those
things and
asking what they're trying to teach you
so i'll go to weed
so i did no no weed i
so situationally i had been smoking a
lot
and before before beginning the
breakup process um shane that i had been
together for 10 years
long time we had a wonderful life we
built together
and you know we came to
this mutual decision that you know we
had run our course which is you know
this isn't so much more like i couldn't
possibly even try to explain the depth
of this
incredibly difficult decision um in in a
quick podcast
sentence um and i don't want to dive too
much into it you know these are still
wounds that are healing they're not
quite scarred so i don't know that my
position is
on them entirely yet um i would like to
wait for me to be stronger and wait to
have more scar tissue before i
jump into those things but nonetheless i
had been smoking quite a bit
and it was a fun it was a nice thing i'm
very polite to myself when i smoke
i enjoy hanging out with myself i enjoy
learning more i
i like to dance and sing around i like
to make
make beats make music i like to draw i
like to i love
riding after after smoking so it just
makes me
a lot it allows me to be the creative
person that i
that i feel that i am without the overly
psychoanalytical
um overly neurotic um
unconfident version of myself kicking in
and
it helps me with inflammation which is a
huge thing with freaking everything in
our food and where i think so many
people are inflamed
thc and cbd these all help with
inflammation a ton
it helps me stretch and breathe which
helps with inflammation
um and it helps with sleep which is a
huge
thing so sleep for me oh man that was
one that was one of the most difficult
so
when i gave up um i i so so i had
still it was 31 days without smoking
but i had tried to to slow my smoking
and even stop it because i started
dealing with
when shane and i were going through the
breakup and i was just like what the
hell is my life
what's going on like what am i gonna do
next
like this house that i'm in at this
current second like uh i'm not
it's not safe anymore it's not my home
anymore like we're moving out of this
house now
um i started dealing with disassociation
very hard
um and weed does not uh hold hands well
with disassociation
sometimes it actually triggers it a lot
more if somebody's dealt with that
disassociation is something just as a
light example
or a quick but not like example
for victims of of rape oftentimes that's
kind of what the mind does is like
there's this acceptance period of you
know saying
you know you're being a woman being
pinned down by another by a strong man
who
she knows i just can't get away from
this at some point her
her brain to protect her from this
incredible pain this incredible tear
that she's going through
will just disassociate which is kind of
your you you disconnect from physical
present
five sense reality and you kind of just
float away and uh
it's this very blank um
numb empty
open but not comfortable but
it's very it's hard to explain
but but disassociation is something that
um
something that i that i started dealing
with actually a couple weeks before
october um and so i had to like kind of
quit
quit on weed there because weed was
activating it more and so i was like
okay i'm not respecting this this plant
medicine really as much as i should be
so i uh i started taking a slow
wean off that slow break and i just
started sleeping terribly instantly like
i couldn't get to sleep
combination of you know not not having
the weed that i was used to not having
the relaxing thing at the end of the
night like i was used to
but also just everything going on in my
life my mind was just racing i was
trying to figure out what's next what's
my future
is this the right decision what's going
on here you know it's this is these are
things that anybody who's gone through
these
through through a breakup or a loss or a
big life change any of these
you know all this this whole life thing
is
is holistic right these all have adverse
effects on other things like sleep and
food intake and urges and depression and
anxiety and blah blah blah
so weed helped me in in a lot of ways
and it was really difficult for me to to
not smoke and not want that comfort and
not want that like
gosh i wish i can kind of just shut off
my brain and listen to some alan watts
or rom das right now
and just you know roll around on the
ground and stretch because i because i
smoked and so i'm not overly thinking
and overly analyzing my situation
but i didn't have access to that so i
had to tough it out um
sleep was really [\h__\h] terrible for
the first couple weeks to be honest
i'm not entirely sure that that was just
not having
having the nightly thc um
or if it was you know that and a
combination of just trying to go through
large changes in my life
right so but but i did get used to it
it started it started after the first i
say two weeks of
not having all these things of of not
having access to all of my vices
it was i was never really concerned that
i would fall back on them i've built up
a pretty
resilient strength that's like if i set
my mind to this thing i'm gonna do it
um and it slowly builds on itself it's
this wonderful thing
but after after the first
you know two weeks maybe i started to
feel it was this
i didn't even give it a thought it's
like yeah of course i want that thing
but
you know i've got 16 more days or i've
got
20 more days like cool and so after
after a while once you really really
have accepted with yourself
i'm not going to do these things it's
not an option
doesn't matter there's no way i'm going
to be tempted to do it to do these
things that i gave up
because i chose to set myself aside and
set
set these things aside in my life for
right now so i can really enjoy
them when they're coming back when i can
really
use them as a way to enjoy my life and
not have them
use me to try to squeeze enjoyment out
of every second
of life you know because life is it
can't just be pleasure
24 7. um i don't think anyway
right uh you got to be down to the real
world so but it was
essentially after the first first couple
weeks it started allowing me to
be excited i started um like oh okay
cool 14 more days right on i'm super
pumped yeah i can't wait to
i'm gonna i'm gonna hit up so and so and
we're gonna go have a beer at this place
or
um like this this coming weekend my
friends are taking me to
to astoria to have a beer and i'm i'm
just super excited about it beer and
pizza
in it but it's something that we
scheduled a few weeks ago and i've been
looking forward to it
but you know something to keep in mind
with with things that
that you don't do all the time they
become that much more important
you know if you had beer and pizza every
single day for a year
i feel like the la the latter half of
that year you're not going to be super
pumped you're not going to be it's not
going to be this special thing
so you know really noting these things
even just our big urge you say you want
to eat a piece of chocolate cake
but you only want it for a little while
you only want it for a small amount you
don't want it to last forever
it's all about balance if you if you had
the taste of chocolate cake in your
mouth for
for you know 10 minutes after you were
already full
after a while you'd be like get this
taste out of my mouth right you wouldn't
you wouldn't want to feel the taste of
chocolate cake
afterwards so when you can notice these
as just feelings notice them as just
urges and then you put these mental
structures up of
i'm not going to indulge in that like
i'm going to
i'm going to look forward to the next
time that i can
but i already decided like oh i had beer
twice this week
well as much as i want to go have
there's always something there's always
a party there's always a friend who hits
you up there's always
um anytime you go to a restaurant like
yeah you can add a beer to it yeah you
can have them
add a margarita to it like should we do
a shot all these things there's
those that [\h__\h] always comes up so if
it's affecting you in a negative way
or it gets a hold of you or you don't
make the right decisions or you're
spending too much money on it or any of
these things
set up those structures because when you
make it to where like oh i only drink a
couple times a month or oh i only
smoke a couple times a month you
it makes it that much more exciting you
become that much more present when you
do it
in in it controls you a lot less
and you use you use these substances
as a way to just kind of put some
sprinkles on on a situation that's
already
very enjoyable like so you don't need
these things but
they add a little bit to them you know
the social lubricant or the
the the self lubricant as it you know
comes when it comes to marijuana
a lot of people it's a huge thing you
know when i started
healing really really tackling and
understanding my depression a couple
years back
weed was a huge factor for me um it
scared the [\h__\h] out of me like i didn't
actually like it that much the first
couple weeks but i kept i was like i
want i know this is helping
um i i'm having a couple glimpses of of
laughter
um uh it's it's sending me into some
sort of
some panic attacks but it's sometimes
it's making me happy i kept like
powering through it
and then before long you know i was able
to just hang out with myself
and just being able to hang out with
yourself like not grabbing your phone
to escape not trying to connect with
someone not seeing what everybody else
is doing
just sitting with yourself like what do
i want to do right now
in in will i allow myself to actually do
it
and will i just let myself have these
things that i kind of feel like
feel like doing you know it sounds weird
for a grown man to say
they you know smoke weed so you can get
by yourself and dance around but
there's some healing in that so if you
can get yourself to that stage
why not you know there's self-love is is
far from corny you know it's
it's uh abnormal but it's something that
we need to to really strive for and
really find ways to get
um to get nowadays so
um
i let's see what else
yoga i did yoga 20 minutes a day
i think that there was there was like
two days where i didn't um
tally the exact times for yoga but i
actually have a pretty good solid
meditation in yoga practice as well so
yoga every day wasn't that far of a
stretch for me
but i think there was two days where i
was i was incredibly depressed
and uh i i i know there was one time
where i went outside
i was doing my morning routine and i
didn't make it 10 minutes i was like
listening to my motivational
videos i had all my workout gear on i
was doing my breath work i was
you know trying to get a sweat chugging
water like all these things but i was
just
um you know some sometimes my my
depression
disorder whatever just really kicks my
ass and i i can't really
i ended up literally um i don't know if
i got 20 minutes and maybe i stretched
for 10 minutes or something
but i ended up like going backside i
just i had to go back to bed like i just
i went back to sleep
and i don't like doing that and
like i guess it's what i needed that day
but it was very defeating i didn't like
it at all
i'm usually someone who's able to even
if i'm having an incredibly bad
depression day
i can even like go for a run and like
i'll cry when i'm running i don't care
as long as i'm getting my body
physically moving because i know it
[\h__\h] helps
but i had a day or two you know just
situationally with all the things going
on my life just really activates that
depressive side of my
of my psyche so overall the
the yoga the stretching uh
recommendations for that for other
people if you want to
take up that habit try stretching before
bed
instead of um like like when you have
that urge to get a snack like it's after
eight or it's after 7 30 or whatever and
like we a lot of us get a snack or we're
watching tv or whatever it is
um maybe try to replace that with
stretching like while you're watching tv
like you you know you're kind of
actively i'm watching this so i can wind
down so it's kind of mindless so i can
you know it's the end of my day i'm
pretty tired i don't want to do much
physical work
like you don't have to put yoga pants on
and you don't have to like
get a gym playlist and you don't have to
you know
set up all these elaborate things like
you could just in your living room
push your put your couch back or don't
even get off the couch
just start moving just start stretching
just start just
vibing like as you're watching your
favorite show just get
moving start breathing like breathe into
your into your tummy
um i think i think before bed yoga helps
our body out a lot um
add water to it of course and then in
in the morning as well like right before
bed and in the morning i think those are
the best times to get any sort of
uh routines in so stretching um
yoga meditation water
all these sorts of things i like to get
up out of bed and it's just the first
thing that i do
is i just start stretching i get up and
i lift my arms up real high
and i bend down i kind of let my head
hang there and i try to get my spinal
column
column moving i try to get this the
spinal fluid going in there
there's a lot of moves on youtube don't
underestimate me youtube
if you just want to do you know i think
we treat yoga
and stretching and movement as this
workout
like it's this thing where you work out
and you sweat so you can burn
this many calories we just think
calories
work out gym gear gyms weights like
that's what we think about
and i think living in in 2020
living in this intricate way for humans
like we've really advanced a lot in our
we've changed our the biological
lifestyle that a human
lives in is very different like working
out even like you know
doing curls like intentionally lifting
up heavy weights and setting them
setting them back down uh you know 80
years ago if you saw someone doing that
you'd be like what in the hell are you
doing you look like
so weird but it's something that comes
with our lifestyle now
we need movement we're no longer you
know
the the thing right after monkeys that
are swinging in the trees and we're no
longer hunting for days and we're no
longer
um you know squatting while we're eating
you know we have these
this comfort these perfect chairs and
uh these padded shoes and
um there's so many things that
biologically
in order to be comfortable we've we've
gone against what our bodies do and so
now we just need
movement and i think that
i'm always saying you know if counting
calories works for you if counting your
steps on your apple watch works for you
if filling up your rings works for you
if uh you know all these things that get
us to work out
if buying the new leggings every month
and looking to fly as [\h__\h]
going to the gym is your thing like
that's what gets you going like dude
hell yeah
that's what gets you in there like
you're working out that's great
but really don't underestimate just
falling on the floor and stretching
just it doesn't even have to be that
long or just looking up on youtube
yoga with adrian i would suggest yoga
beginner yoga none of it's hard none of
it you do wrong
it's just feeling your own inners your
own body getting these things going
around it's like
yeah maybe you ate less calories but
your digestive system isn't working
because
your muscles are all tight and the water
in your body is not moving around and
things are inflamed so they're stopping
different things in your digestive
system from working properly
so uh i encourage anybody to you know
eat healthy drink your water
go to the gym burn your calories like
kill it in the gym if that's your
thing but anything is better than
nothing
so stretch before bed if you can or
right in the morning when you wake up or
just make it a habit through the day you
know just
as you're watching tv like every hour or
every half hour
every time uh it switches shows maybe
just get up and start kind of stretching
your neck like you could still be
watching the tv
start stretching your arms start moving
your legs like you don't have to follow
an exact routine you don't have to break
a sweat you have to go put on that
freaking nike headband
just move it's very important nowadays
to what humans are
is is movement
so i think
um did i go over social media
social media use um yeah i felt
i know that i mentioned that i felt
lonely without social media and that was
very true
um not having someone you know being a
relationship for 10 years and not having
the same person that you normally text
just about everything you know you're
just like it's just your best friend you
just talk to him all the time you don't
even think about it you just
you just pull your phone out and you
talk to him that's just something that
happens nowadays you know
humans haven't had phones and magical
rectangles in our pockets our whole life
like instant access to whoever we want
to see
at all times or whoever we want to talk
to or whatever we want to say to whoever
we have in our lives to say it to
that's a pretty [\h__\h] new thing like
we fairly new
so noticing
uh you know the
the comforts that we get from that you
know yeah
like how often um i'd have quite a few
friends kind of texting me checking in
on me like you know just wanted to make
sure i'm doing great good and
i'm so grateful for that and there i
have some wonderful people in my life
um but just just i really what i noticed
without social media again
is that it gives me extreme comfort
you know when when you're in an awkward
position or you're feeling lonely
or um you're in a position where you
think people are looking at you
or you're in a public place or you're
waiting somewhere or you're on the
toilet
like before before things even start
going on down there i feel like my
phone's already in my hand it's just a
habitual thing
so just as when we walk
outside to the car every day we don't
we don't think about how put hand to
handle
grip handle pull with left arm bend at
left elbow
step to the right side so we can get out
of the way for our door
get in cart like we don't think about
those things they're just habitual
we just to when you go outside to go to
work you just go get in your damn car
and you drive
but there's a lot of small processes
that happen in between there and we can
bring awareness to those things
so your phone when you're sitting there
and you're trying to be present or
you're watching something or you're with
people
or you're waiting or you're walking to
or from somewhere
or you just get in your car you just get
off a phone call all these instances in
our life
where we don't really think about it we
don't bring awareness to ourselves we
don't bring
um awareness to the situation or what
we're actually doing but
before you know it you're just scrolling
you're just looking through your phone
and a lot of that is kind of our
our let's see
our character identity kind of
avoiding discomfort avoiding pain
avoiding
boredom our inability to sit with
ourself
is uh a problem
it's a problem um as someone who's been
i've been very addicted to social media
before
um i i still have it like i still i
notice
myself like i check these things i like
being in contact with people i like
having
cool conversations i like seeing things
that people are talking about
i um i like attention from it
i i'm very something that i had to come
to terms with
a couple years back i was like holy [\h__\h]
i i am
obsessed with other people's approval i
love other people's approval
i really want people to tell me what i'm
doing is
wonderful i really want people to tell
me what i'm doing is
original you know or even just
the the really low hanging stuff like
you know i want to be told that i'm good
looking i want to be told that i'm hot
you know all this [\h__\h] that is so normal
in the human brain
because of our culture um but
we let it control our actions a lot and
i just
i don't know if that's what's best for
our life
in the long run you know we're we're
gonna die one day
you know this life is life because
there's death
um this this wonderful thing we have
here i don't think we should just fill
it with trying to get as many dopamine
hits as we can all the time
um if you've watched the social social
dilemma on
netflix i've recommended that multiple
times
tristan harris is kind of one of the
leaders of that
but uh it kind of uh explains to you
um in in it explains to us
how we're manipulated and controlled and
um we are we are the data
being sold back to us our attention is
is a currency um
and it's it's almost this unfair thing
that's happened to us with social media
and i think bringing awareness to it
um bringing it to our consciousness like
in front of us like wait
okay i pulled up my phone and i was just
scrolling like why did i do that not not
to make ourselves feel bad
not to feel ashamed not to
feel like we're weird and alone but i
think
so many of us don't understand exactly
what we're trying to get out of these
things
um like why is it that that we spend
so long uh editing our face or
getting rid of all of our blemishes or
um
taking 25 photos so we can pick the best
one
you know there's a lot of this stuff
that's super fun
like social media and having cameras in
our pockets at all
times taking snapshots of our life like
it's so
cool it really is one of the most
incredible things in in
filters and uh photo editing software at
your fingertips like i enjoy the crap
out of this stuff it's so cool but
what is it doing to my internal like
what is it doing to my confidence
what isn't making me think about myself
um
i had a podcast guess my friend ricky
nevereddy who's a who's a power lifter
competitive power lifter
and we're talking about ego lifting and
i used to always work out i loved
working out
um but i feel like the last the last
couple years before i kind of like
stopped hitting like the
the weights so hard and i started
getting more into yoga and kind of
staying at home doing more running i was
doing a lot of ego lifting i was
essentially like
i didn't feel good about myself so i
went into the gym i would drink
pre-workout so i can get that pump
pre-workout really makes you get like a
pump in your muscles especially the ones
are working
and i would by the time i left the gym
when i looked in the mirror i was like
excited because i'm like okay i look i
look tight now i look strong
my muscles look big i look pumped up my
posture is better all this stuff
i felt confident when i left the gym so
i was basically trying to get like this
ego pump like just make my
make myself feel good about myself not
in a
i came to the gym and i did my work and
i'm proud of myself for the work but it
was this
uh affirmation towards myself for my
physique
and you know that's that's a part of our
brains it truly is but i think that's
also
worth taking a look at um i think
i think when we're
putting our highlight reels out when
we're putting our
our best self out all the time
it's interesting what that does to us
it's interesting what that does
inevitably to make us compare ourselves
to other people
um it's interesting how we how we think
about
other people who aren't up to that
comparison
in our eyes um it's interesting like
looking at photos of ourselves and
saying uh or
um we look at a photo and we instantly
look for our flaws
like i'll you know instantly look like
oh do i have any acne in that photo or
like when i had more weight one thing i
would do when i would see like photo
like we take group photo when it's
when a photo is just like hey i'm having
fun with my friends let's get a snapshot
to remember this [\h__\h]
that's what a photo is inherently right
but when you end up taking a bunch of
photos
and immediately everybody who looks at
the photo we will crowd around the phone
to look at it and we all just look for
our flaws like
i look kind of fat in that one and then
we kind of adjust our shirt or
oh my god my nose looks so big in that
or uh
oh that color doesn't look good on me or
oh my skin tone next to my friend's skin
tone looks shitty like what what is that
doing to us what is that doing to our to
our personality and our character traits
and is that good is that healthy is that
something that we would want for our
children
is that something we would want for
younger kids to grow up and like really
not comprehend that they're doing i
think when you can bring awareness to
all these things
so quitting social media for a month or
or taking up the break
from these apps for a month um turning
off notifications that's a huge one i
did that
many years ago and that's that's
something that i still when people have
notifications on still
it actually catches me off guard i'm
like oh [\h__\h] i forgot that not everybody
like like people still use notifications
uh
because it's just it constantly pulls us
out of our day
i think there's a balance i think
there's there is a way of enjoying it
but i think if you begin to notice how
split our attention spans are you know a
lot of people identify with having adhd
now and i think actually at this point
our relationships with our phones and
social media and
entertainment has actually created adhd
and a majority of our like young
technological minds
um or what we would call adhd
rather what what we identify as and say
our attention span
we can't focus or blah blah and it's
just part of us now we just brush it off
like
we don't think twice about it but it's
actually very important to be able to
pay attention to things and be able to
focus on things
and be able to not just passively
consume
everything but sometimes be able to
focus and actively consume new
information
but taking a break from from social
media
is it's great i i definitely feel that
next year
if i do sober october again i feel like
i will certainly do that
it helps me i i'm back on social media
now
i feel like i've uh the the first couple
days it's funny because it was my
birthday
um two days ago and so i was i was i was
back into it but i was just like let
dude let yourself just whenever you feel
like pulling out your phone
like you're getting messages all day on
these on these platforms on
you getting texts whatever like let
yourself pull it out and like just read
that and really try to just
just feel what your friends are telling
you and people in
all these wonderful people wishing you
happy birthday i really tried to just
like
let myself rip you know like oh my my my
phone
uh my text message went off so i had a
notification or
like check instagram or whatever it is
like every 10 minutes if i had the time
you know not
every 10 minutes but i i let myself
rip so to say and it was really
enjoyable
um and i think that's good for days like
birthdays where you just like
no no limits or maybe it's your day off
you're like dude i'm just gonna like
just as where we would binge watch
netflix you know like maybe there's some
days where you're like it's sunday i'm
just gonna
i'm gonna [\h__\h] hang out on my phone
today i'm just gonna enjoy
the coolness of social media i'm just
gonna enjoy whatever
youtube algorithms have for me to to
play next i'm going to read a bunch of
articles i'm going to whatever
notice that it will make you actually
kind of weirdly exhausted
if you did do that all day but setting
boundaries maybe setting
one day a week where you let yourself
almost like a cheat day with your phone
and you just allow yourself to lay in
bed and do it
or even just set set limits around i
never allow myself to
check the social media while i'm in bed
maybe that's what's going to work for
you maybe you try that for 30 days and
you realize that it makes you care a lot
less about the political nonsense going
on
maybe you don't allow notifications go
directly to your to your screen
maybe you don't touch your phone for the
first hour of the day you don't read any
news for the first hour of the day
our whole our whole society has really
been changed and formed and morphed by
uh social media and not just social
media like
what social media has done we've got to
look at what it does to
what the human being is like if you're
an alien who's hovering in a spaceship
above the earth and you've been kind of
watching
humans for the last couple hundred years
and you realize like
what's something that has changed
everything that they do and how they
they interact with one another um what
they think about like if you're
you're in the alien ship and you're able
to somehow see every human being's
thoughts
whether it's about themselves or other
people or about what they're doing or
how often they're not in the present
moment because they're just thinking
thinking thinking or
arguing these things in their brain uh
i think that if you look at at social
media
it's very much changed this whole thing
here it's
the the human experience has been vastly
morphed
and flipped around and sped up and
just gotten weirdo because of social
media
just what it has done to our culture to
our civilization i mean
i guess you could even say what the
internet has done now that we've had a
couple years you know quite a few years
of
of the internet i'm not even that long
iphone came out 2007.
that's just something to think about
[Music]
i guess asking yourself when you pull
out social media when you're posting
when you're doing these things like why
am i doing this like why am i really
doing this
and you don't have to tell other people
you don't have to go on a podcast and
talk about your insecurities about it
you could just really ask yourself like
huh does this
does this actually make me feel better
or does this just kind of like
is this kind of just like what a smoker
gets out of a cigarette like where
you know a lot of cigarette smokers they
don't like that they smoke they insult
themselves every time when they smoke
not all of them but a lot of times
they're like yeah i know it sucks i know
it gives me cancer but here i am her
like are you doing that with social
media are you doing that
with your non-movement practices
are you doing that with your water
intake like is it a popular thing for
you to hate water
which you know is that part of your
identity
um covering up
the things that are killing us um and
just joking them off
i don't know i i i i've began kind of
like trying to fight my urges and began
trying to control them
or try to work with them you know like
i'm a human being and i have urges and i
have addictions and i have
um i have habits and i have
things that like you know maybe i wish i
had better control of
but i don't have to completely just bow
down to them i can
take a grip i can grab them by the horns
and and get a little bit stronger little
by little
by just just trying you know trying to
change i think that we
we grow up in this world especially in
the western culture
and there's this weird thing that we
don't realize is there
that says once you're done with high
school if you don't go to college
or uh after you're done with any sort of
schooling
like that's who you are that that's this
is who you are
you're done you're just gonna live that
out instead of
learning to change like you can really
change
everything about yourself like you you
could change you could slowly become
aware of your habits
and then ask yourself is this a habit
that i want to take with me
is this a habit that i want to go on for
the next 60 70 years of my life
is this habit beneficial for me why did
i get this habit
what does this habit bring me is it
beneficial to me
where did i learn that this is what i
should be doing
who in my life when i was younger did
this thing around me that made it okay
um
what how does this make me feel the next
day not only the night of you know
so i think just
just
blues dreaming uh uh
just be becoming aware of our habits
becoming aware of our addictions um
two more things i'll round this up i
know this video is getting pretty long
um
but my my running goal uh i
i my running goal was to run five times
a week
and i think that i pretty much hit it um
i don't know if i can
consistently did like you know monday
through friday then i take saturday
sunday off
but there was times where i did run
seven days in a row eight days in a row
and i would take like two sometimes
three days off
um just uh just you know trying to
muster up sometimes i
sometimes i go too extreme which is
something that's that's good to know
something one more thing i learned
a little bit more about myself is
sometimes there's too much that we put
on ourselves
so i was able to get my running goals in
i'm feeling great i've really enjoyed
running
and it starts to populate like what can
i do with this running thing i've always
ran these i've like these spar
spartan races uh warrior dash um
like like all the like the 5k or five
mile runs or
or the eight mile runs whatever it is
i've i really enjoy those and i haven't
done those in the last couple years
i've kept active and kept running i like
outdoor running i really love trail
running like going up on a hike
somewhere
and running through the trails there
it's fantastic
um but so so when you
there's this gift you can give yourself
when
you stick to something like when you're
like running every day it starts
becoming
your identity you're like oh i guess i
am a runner now
and then if you're someone like me like
my head is always in the future and i'm
visiting the now
right so my head is always like what can
i do with this like
what do i want to do like what how can i
one-up this thing
and so i noticed i really started giving
it to myself more as
as i was running more and more every day
i was like man i am a runner
and like i can actually run a pretty
good distance and you know i wouldn't
mind running a
a barefoot marathon or i wouldn't mind
running um
a marathon in general like i haven't
done a marathon i've done these other
races but i've never done a marathon or
like
i wonder if i could run 100 miles in a
week
or you know you start allowing yourself
to set these like cool goals
that if you completed them they would
feel really good
and then you allow yourself to start
thinking about them through the day like
even when you're not running
so it's almost when you have discipline
to do these things little by little
it starts opening up these things in
your psyche to where you can kind of
daydream and actually allow yourself to
grab those daydreams and say like
oh [\h__\h] i can actually do that thing um
it's it's this
this little trick to self-belief you
know believing in yourself
is is one of the more powerful things
you can really accomplish a lot you can
really
start allowing yourself to have times
for these things in your mind to think
about like
having time for yourself to write down
certain things like i want to accomplish
this
within the next five years and then when
you start little by little actually
doing steps towards it you start really
saying
man i wonder if i can really do this
thing you know anybody who's ever
accomplished anything great they had to
believe in themselves so don't allow the
believe in yourself
or love yourself or shoot for the shoot
for the stars like all that all those
sort of
catch phrases and stuff don't allow
those to be corny don't allow those to
be like
lame don't allow being happy and and
having self belief to be something
that's like
for other people like that's something
that the motivational like
weird self-love hippy-dippy people do
like no man you're a human you've got to
allow yourself to have the thoughts of
what you want your future to be and you
can start taking
steps towards those goals so
the one thing that i did of course i
waited till the end maybe i thought i
was going to forget this one
one thing that i would that i certainly
say um i don't know if failed is that is
the correct word
maybe i'll dissect that but i did not
complete my writing goal
i had the first few days i had a lot of
good momentum
i sat down and i wrote a few pages um
i wrote oh man it was probably like five
days
but then i just i started not getting it
i started
i was just too tired for my morning my
other the rest of my morning routine
and i would come in and i would just
like just be exhausted i wouldn't have a
lot of mental energy left and i would
i was dealing with some depression and
like you know this this heartbreak
situation that i'm trying to navigate
through
so i'll just be overly exhausted from
thinking too much about it
and uh and i didn't complete my goals
and
i just moved into this new space and so
i was trying to i wanted the writing
goal because i was trying to
create a habit of like well this is just
what i do like the last step in my
morning routine when i come back into
this room i sit at this desk over here
that's not my regular desk like i have
this is my like
audio creation like uh
you know music making djing desk then i
have a whole other desk that i set up
that has all my paperwork and all of my
writing and all my poetry and all that
stuff
so i was hoping to have the goal or
have the habit built of every day i
write
something like even if it's garbage even
if it's just positive affirmations
because that's all my brain has today
just get it done but i did not complete
that task that is something that
was interesting i had a couple days
where i wrote a good amount
outside of so the first four or five
days whatever it was
i did good and then after that i only
had a
a couple days of uh really getting any
sort of writing done
other than that it was something i ended
up like neglecting like i i
stopped even like thinking about it like
i almost
allowed myself to accept the defeat like
i guess i'm not doing that goal
so that's a bummer um i've been trying
not to make myself
feel too much shame about it and i know
that i get too extreme sometimes which
that happens to a lot of us
um so that that's a goal that i want to
not give up on though because i really
enjoy writing um it makes me feel
fulfilled it makes me feel like my
thoughts are getting out there
it makes me feel a little more sane i
know it's it's just
it's just beneficial in so many ways
like there's all these different aspects
of writing
i did continue to take i'm just someone
who has always taken notes in my phone i
have
if i ever die and you want some good
weird guy content just go through my
phone
and look through my notes and i have
hundreds and hundreds of pages of just
ideas and
poetry and uh things that i want for my
future
and affirmations and all these things so
i was able to write on my phone a little
bit
um but anybody else who wants to um
who wants to partake in writing uh if
you want to make that a habit
you know just just do it just try it
you know try it for a week try it for
five days try it for
every wednesday you have an alarm that
goes off
at 7 35 a.m and it says
write one paragraph or write one thing
that you enjoyed doing or
even even just a habit of writing your
daily schedule
like wake up and say what do i want to
accomplish today or wake up and say what
do i want to accomplish tomorrow and so
you're always a step ahead
so these are all important tools
important tactics
um i am certainly going to continue
going forth with trying to get myself to
write a little bit more and rebuild that
habit here in the new house
my old place i wrote a shitload but it's
something that i got to rebuild because
i'm in a new environment right i'm in a
new space i'm in a new headspace
i'm in a new life it feels like so i've
got to get those habits going
i'm going to work on that i'm going to
continue to drink as close to a gallon a
day as possible
i'm not going to get light with myself
from that i've been doing a lot of yoga
i've been running a lot still
i think that that doing this for 30 days
really helped me
just start to have my identity lean more
into it like this is just something that
i do and
our our personality is our personal
reality right you know we
we we habitually do all these things
and that's they become who we are we
aren't just
who we are we're born exactly this one
person and we're just acting that out
no like you can set intention and you
can set
uh boundaries up for yourself and you
can
you can
you can really it's almost like hacking
evolution right evolution is always
going towards this
this one this one thing like
we for so long it was our goal to just
survive
like survival of the fittest like make
sure we're not getting killed by the
lions
um make sure we're like like we're able
we have thumbs and so we can make spears
and we can
hunt however any fish we need to just
survive survive survive for so many
years
and now we're kind of at this
incredible place for humanity and in
what we are
to where we don't just have to survive i
mean more people die from obesity now
than starving like
really think about that but also more
people die from suicide now than ever
in the if more people die from suicide
than homicide
so i think we need to take a look at
what we are and what we're doing and
what we're thinking about and how we get
to those places like suicide and how we
get to places like defeat and how we
become how we become something that just
continues to go about our habits and our
our default mode network and never
really changes
and never really gets out of those
divots in our brain you know
neuroplasticity is
real you can create who you want to be
little by little by just making
incremental changes
um so i guess i'll i'll round it out
i think i covered everything um
i'm looking forward to the next one next
sober october um
i if anybody wants to participate i know
it's a long way right away but
you know hit me up around the time we
could do a big group
i really appreciate everybody else who
hopped on on there with me in their own
ways
i i did what what worked for me in my
life um
i've been drinking from a young age i've
been smoking for a long time
um i've been um uh
you know all these things that
i basically what i'm saying is i i chose
i chose things that really seemed
specific to me
and i chose where i'm at with them you
know if this was like right at the
if this was three years ago this would
have been way too extreme i think i
would have failed like
all the goals but now i've slowly built
up this resilience i've slowly built up
these habit
these habits and i've slowly built up my
strength and my ability to like have
positive self-talk and work on myself
and really believe
like i could stick to my guns here like
i got this i made the decision
that i'm not going to do this thing for
31 days so it's not going to [\h__\h]
happen for 31 days
and really sticking to it um so
i invite you to pick a month pick a
friend
that like really 100 like it's not an
option we're not slipping up on this
no [\h__\h] matter what pick a friend
your spouse your sister
your mom even like whatever whoever is
in your life who you're like
hey you want to try this thing where we
just
do do this or don't do this for 30 days
for one month or two weeks even just
stick to something and don't bend on it
uh it could literally be a i'm not gonna
eat a dairy product for the month of
december
i'm not going to have
more than one glass of wine a night for
the month of december
i'm not going to uh
uh you know i'm not going to
neglect my body for this like like try
to get very specific with yourself like
something that is a
yes or no a pass or fail write it down
give in to it like just just do it just
believe that you can do it and stick to
it
i think there's real strength in these
um at the end of my
at the end of my 31 day sober october i
i felt great honestly i i felt powerful
i felt strong
i was actually very proud of myself um
i felt my body felt really good my
uh my trust in my own psyche felt really
good you know i'm someone when you deal
with
with uh you know like like major
depressive disorder
and uh you know i used to kind of have
like
what we would call adhd ocd
just these like intense thoughts where i
just get caught and obsessively start
thinking about things on in loops
it really helps me identify less with my
faults it helps me identify less with
like
the things that are like well these are
the shitty things about my brain and i
guess i gotta deal with them and that's
who i am forever
and it helps you really have faith that
oh i could like
i could heal myself of all this stuff i
could get better in this way i could
make this part of myself better
i could actually accomplish that crazy
task that i want to accomplish
so there's really something about it
um uh i guess i guess we'll end it we'll
round it up here um discipline equals
freedom
um that that's the thing that there's
there's there's power in all of this
stuff um
you know when you're when you're a slave
to
the things that you set up for yourself
it's a lot better than being a slave to
your random urges or you know um
just just thinking like a boy all the
time or just being a brat all the time
there's nothing to be ashamed of if you
don't have control of all of your habits
and urges but
there is strength and real just
badassness ahead of you if you can grab
it by the horns
um
yeah i think that's it
i appreciate you guys listening to the
podcast if you had any questions about
my sober october or you have any
questions about anything that i
mentioned today
i'm i like to you know i really try to
value authenticity when it comes to this
podcast
i really try to be open and transparent
and try to try to talk about things that
people may be thinking but they don't
know their thinking
i'm just trying to expand
expand who we are and expand what we are
and you know i
i i want to help people save themselves
from themselves
you know i've suffered a lot of this
crap myself i've
suffered my own mind in many ways for
many years
and there's real freedom when you take
discipline in when you start trying to
insert your own morals and values and
ethics
and just getting better and improving
and evolving into the best versions of
yourself so
self-actualization for all i believe in
you
please please please stretch a little
bit
breathe from only your nose close your
mouth try to be more conscious breathe
slower
stretch more drink more water again
and just love yourself man so i'll see
you guys later
hit me up if you have any questions add
me on instagram
jacob from the internet send me a
message on there that's probably where
i'm the most
active if you have any questions this
will probably be on youtube as well you
can comment on there
if you have any ideas for the future of
the junkyard love podcast
or um guests that you think may be good
i'm open to uh the possibilities there
so
we're getting up there in numbers and
i'm getting
i'm getting better and better at the
podcast thing i'd say
so i'm getting to where i'm uh more
confident in
allowing myself to get a little bit
bigger guests a little bit
um more known guests with a little more
popularity so
lots of cool things to come in the month
of november a couple new guests
and some more following then so take
care of yourself listeners
if you did enjoy the podcast or you are
enjoying the podcast
or you like these conversations or you
want to hear more please
like comment subscribe put it on the
thumb drive and put it in your
neighbor's mailbox
or send it to your dad just share it i
appreciate it take care
[Music]
uh
knowledge is power
[Music]
you